So you have just tuned in, to a rather interesting
IPL Match
Just the 5 overs are remaining, and you start
craving some crispy Pakodas
So you think to yourself, Mom, Please
make some Pakodas for me
But, Obviously Mom says that you have just had lunch
This is not the time for Pakodas
So you dont have any other choice,
and you turn to your phone.
And you start browsing immediately,
on swiggy or zomato
and you start ordering your pakodas
Just a few mins later, and there your doorbell rings
So have you ever wondered, what is the story behind these
people, and how they delivery these things to you?
How is it that they have come at this young age to become delivery boys
Today, we decided, All of us walked to the streets of Pune, and meet them ourselves
Thank you Brother, The first thing that I want to talk to you about
Is since when are you doing this job?
3 years
Is it full time or part time?
Full time
Does Zomato pay for your daily expenses? or you have to bear them?
we have to bear them...
So how many orders do you complete in a day?
15-20...
How do you get the zomato orders in your phone?
The server assigns the orders to us
Is there any incident that happened during your tenure?
Maybe during delivery..?
Nothing as such has happened till today but some people do
COD (Cash on Delivery)
then we have to convince them to do COD
or do online payment
And in Pune city most of the time the delivery
location is not accurate
then the customer has to guide them to the correct
location and gps is also not always accurate
Have you faced any problems in these covid times?
In these difficult times our company zomato had given us special instructions
to where and how to keep the order and we used to leave the order on the table or chair
that was kept outside the door and then we used to take the photo and notify
the customer through the app and the customer used to see that the order has arrived
and accordingly the customer would come and take the order
While you are delivering the order has there been any issue
with the security guard or while picking up the order from the restaurant
The restaurants delay the order sometimes but we get to know it
And because of this have ever faced any issue from the customer
No, as soon as we receive the call of the customer we tell them about
the delay in order and it shows the customer in the app
that the rider has picked up your order from the restaurant,
and sometimes customer asks them about the order
so they tell them about the order that has been delayed and
the further situation will be updated on the app
Any Problems, issues with the security guards?
No,not all
Any problem you faced with them?
no never, we adjust.
We have our University project regarding the food delivery boys
So when these delivery boys come, do you indulge in any conversation with them?
We take his number, we ask his name, where he wants to deliver the food, and thats it.
Have you ever faced any conflicts with them
No, we dont talk much. They do their work, we do ours
First of all thank you for time and having a small talk with us.
Since when are you working here?
5 Years
So we asked the delivery boys about their confrontation with you,
they said that food vendors take alot of time to prepare the food.
It takes time to prepare food
They said that even if they arrive late to collect food it is still not ready.
It takes time for us to prepare as there ae many orders.
If we prepare it in advance it will become cold till it reaches the customer
Does the always happen or you manage it
No we manage it all the time. This doesn't happen often
When the delivery boys come, is your coversation with them limited to work?
No no limited, we ask them their id and order id,
if the food is ready we give it, if not we ask them wait
Do you know any of the delivery boys personally?
no i dont
There are many delivery boys, its hard to keep track
If there are no orders, how do you pass your time?
I often use social media and surf on the internet